RUBEN A. SANCHEZ

| 1 (702) 779-3 | 3979 | nchez.com in rubenasanchez |
|----------------------|---|---|
| EDUCATION | | |
| 2015 2015 | B.A. Linguistics B.S. Cognitive Science | University of California, Santa Cruz University of California, Santa Cruz |
| PUBLICATION | | |
| 2019 | Zyzik, E.C., & Sanchez, R.A. (2019). Beyond accuracy: Heritage speakers' performance on two kinds of acceptability judgment tasks. <i>Applied Psycholinguistics</i> , 40(3), 645-671. http://doi.org/10.1017/S0142716418000760 | |
| AWARDS | | |
| 2021 | Macquarie Group Scholarship | |
| RESEARCH EXPERIENCE | | |
| 2017 to 2018 | Data Analyst - Bilingualism Research Lab Responsible for conducting data pre-processing, coding analysis, inferential analysis, data visualizations, and of | |
| 2016 | Annotator - Natural Language & Dialogue Systems Annotated social media content for computational mo narrative summarizations. | University of California, Santa Cruz deling via language entrainment and |
| 2013 to 2014 | Research Assistant - Cognitive Science Department Coded acoustic data with Praat and video data with study. | University of California, Santa Cruz After Effects for a linguistic phonetic |
| 2012 | Research Assistant - Linguistics Department Developed, implemented, and completed a phonologica stimuli, scheduled and ran participants, as well as ana | |
| TEACHING EXPERIENCE | | |
| 2020 | Academic Success Mentor Served as advisor for student at risk of loosing residency due to failed coursework. - Guided student through studying best practices. - Developed a strategy plan for completing assignments. - Advised on stress coping mechanisms and directed to resources. - Student successfully completed the quarter and graduated. | |
| 2018 to 2019 | Private Tutor Tutored college students in mathematics. | |
| | | |

Tutored international students in English composition.

Volunteer Tutor

2018 to 2019

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Expertise Cognitive research, neurolinguistics, phonetic psycholinguistics, data visualization,

web development, illustration, and 2D animation.

Research Interested in investigating the neural circuitry responsible for the assignment of semantic

Interests coding onto phonetic units perceived as linguistically relevant.

Also interested in multimodal communicative strategies for human computer interaction.

Programming Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GIT, CLI, bash, LATEX, markdown

Research E-Prime, SuperLab, Praat, Audacity, ELAN, SPSS, Mendeley, Zotero

Design Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Figma, Invision, Blender

Leadership Project Management, Team Building, Issue Resolution

Languages English, Italian, Spanish, learning Japanese

CURRENT PROJECTS

2021 Web Based Interactive 3D Brain Model

Teaching myself advanced 3D modeling methods for developing an interactive model of the human brain which displays areas currently known to be pertinent to the perception and production of sounds relevant to language.

- Completed design of graphical user interface.
- Completed engineering of information architecture.
- Completed development of shell infrastructure.
- Conducting formal literature review for content incorporation.